Inventory to the Lorelei D. Ritchie Interviews, 1992
Hoover Institution Archives
Lorelei D. Ritchie Interviews,
1992
93045
Ritchie, Lorelei D., interviewer
9 phonotape cassettes (1.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Interviews with Panamanian politicians, journalists, businessmen, and university officials, relating to political, economic and human rights conditions in Panama
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1993.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Panama--Politics and government--1981-; Panama--Economic conditions--1979-; Civil rights--Panama; Panama; Phonotapes
Inventory
Brief Description of Interviewees
for collection of tapes catalogued
in the Panama collection of the Hoover archives.
Interviewer: Lorelei D. Ritchie
All interviews conducted in Panama City.
- Interviewees:
  - Nicolás Ardito Barletta. December 17, 1992. Director General and Chairman of the Board of the International Center for Economic Growth (ICEG). President of Panma 1984 to 1985. Vicepresident Latin America and Caribbean region World Bank 1978-1984. Governor for Panama at World Bank 1978. Board of Directors for Tower Bank. Founder and first chairperson for the Board of Directors of Banco Latinoamericano. (Tape Tape 1)
    Interview in English.
  - Guillermo Sánchez Borbón. December 21, 1992. Leading Noriega-opposition writer. Newspaper editor for the independent La Prensa of Panama City. (Tape Tape 2)
    Interview in Spanish.
  - Guillermo Chapman. December 15, 1992. Founder and Director of business consulting group INDESA of Panama City. (Tape Tape 3)
  - Tomás Herrera. December 22, 1992. Lawyer in Panama City. Leading lawyer of the Civic Crusade, an association of civic groups and professionals formed in June 1987 in protest of the Noriega regime. (Tape Tape 4)
  - Stanley Muschett. December 18, 1992. Rector of Universidad Santa Maria la Antigua of Panama City since June of 1990. Chair of the Church Commission on Justice and Peace, which overviews human rights, since creation in 1991. (Tape Tape 5)
  - Herasto Reyes.December 18, 1992. Newspaper editor at independent La Prensa. (Tape Tape 6)
  - Mario Rogñoni. December 16, 1992. Senator and Financial Secretary of the Democratic Revolutionary Party (PRD), the official party of the dictatorship formed in 1978. Prominant spokesperson and media correspondant for the Noriega regime. Minister of Commerce for Noriega 1988-1989. (Tape Tape 7)
    Interview mostly in Spanish.
  - Eduardo Vallarino. December 17, 1992. Ambassador to the United States February to April 1991. Ambassador to the United Nations December 20, 1989 to February 1991. Member of PDC (Christian Democrat Party). (Tape Tape 8)
  - Carlos Zuñiga.December 17, 1992. Rector of the Universidad de Panamá. (Tape Tape 9)